

www.heiux.com tomas@heiux.com +48 500 309 303

Work eligibility: EU (Polish citizen) China (family permit)

# Tomas Czarnecki

a UX Designer

with an Intercultural Background

## **Personal Statement**

A passionate **User Experience Designer**, a **Problem Solver** with more than 6 years of overseas working experience.

Excellent **algorithmic thinking** skills and mission to create logical experiences combining user and business needs. Proven track record of intercultural work experience, including project managing roles.

Always focusing on providing experiences that are profitable and precisely adapted to the target group's needs.

Could contribute to your digital products since the research phase, through prototyping and front-end development. Additionally could help to upgrade existing products by providing heuristic evaluation, analytics, and user testing.

# **Professional Experience**

**08.2019 - now** 8 months

Freelance Designer • Hei UX • Worldwide

Skills: self-learning, design thinking, usability testing, UX process, prototyping Tools: Adobe XD, XMind, Trello, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign, Html, CSS, JavaScript

- After leaving the full-time position, works as a freelance Architectural Designer;
- Works location independently with European and Chinese clients;
- In spare time between project contributes UX Design to Open Source software;

06.2017 - 07.2019

2 years 1 month

Project Architect • SEVEN International • Guizhou, China

Skills: Chinese, management, leadership, working with tight deadlines, recruiting Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Lumion, Adobe InDesign/Photoshop

- Successfully led team of 10 Chinese-only speaking designers;
- Simultaneously managed teams located on 2 continents: in China and Poland;
- Provided conceptual designs for 4 Social Hosing projects and 5 local Banks;
- Led recruitment processes of 12 junior staff-members (for Polish office);
- Prepared series of Rhinoceros 3D courses (in Chinese office);
- Led client meetings and presentations for Chinese customers;

06.2016 - 06.2017

1 year

Architect • PWD Architecture • Beijing, China

Skills: sketching, research, concept design, working with tight deadlines Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Grasshopper, C# Scripting, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign

- Played a crucial role in winning 21 million m<sup>2</sup> Urban Planning competition;
- Saved hundreds of working hours by building an Urban Planning Library:
- Taught series of Grasshopper workshops for coworkers:
- Introduced parametric design methodology;

04.2015 - 05.2016

1 year 1 month

#### Junior Architect • MAD Architects • Beijing, China

Skills: parametric design, algorithmic thinking, genetic algorithms, optimisation Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Grasshopper, C# Scripting, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign

- Was the main architect and developer of a Scripting Library;
- Was a key member of the company's Parametric Research Group;
- Prepared a series of 5 lectures about Parametric Design: Grasshopper;
- Saved hundreds of working hours by providing complex parametric models;
- Used genetic algorithms to optimize facades of double-curved surfaces;

08.2014 - 02.2015

7 months

Junior Architect • SEVEN International • Poznan, Poland and Guizhou, China Skills: Chinese, intercultural communication, management, concept design; Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign, AutoCAD

- Spent 3 months-long internship in the Chinese office;
- Provided conceptions of buildings that were later realized by Chinese team;
- Responsible for official registration of the Polish branch of the company;
- Organized a new office: rent of space, computers, and software;

09.2013 - 06.2014

9 months

Construction Site Intern • Budnex Developer • Gorzow, Poland

- Helped a construction site manager to supervise the quality of construction;
- Measured construction progress and calculated contractor's payments;

11.2012 - 02.2013

4 months

**Construction Site Manager/Translator** • Kaja Horeca Interieurs • Netherlands

Provided Polish-English translation on construction sites;

### **Formal Education**

09.2014 - 04.2015 8 months Building and Environment Ph.D. • Poznan Univeristy of Technology • Poland

- 2 semesters of Ph.D. studies realized at Faculty of Civil Engineering:
- Supervisor: prof. Piotr Marciniak:
- Focused on Parametric Design: Grasshopper, C#, Algorithmic Thinking;

09.2011 - 06.2012

10 months

Architecture Erasmus • Istanbul Technical University • Turkey

- 2 semesters of international exchange:
- Parametric Design course by associate prof. Ozan Önder Özener;

03.2011 - 06.2014 3 years 4 months Architecture M.Sc. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

- Graduated with the highest A-grade;
- Supervisor: prof. Piotr Marciniak;

09.2007 - 02.2011

3 years 6 months

Architecture B.Eng. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

- Supervisor: prof. Ewa Pruszewicz-Sipińska, dean of the Architecture Faculty;
- Received 2 rector's scholarships for great achievements in education;

09.2006 - 06.2007

10 months

Computer Science B.Eng. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

• 2 semesters of B.Eng. studies in English;

# **Courses and Trainings**

Master Digital Product Design: UX Research & UI Design • by Rob Sutcliffe UX Design & User Experience Design Course • by Daniel Walter Scott User Experience Design - Adobe XD UI UX Design • by Daniel Walter Scott Responsive Web Design - HTML5 CSS3 Bootstrap • by Daniel Walter Scott UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy, Design, Development • by Joe Natoli The Complete Web Developer in 2019: Zero to Mastery • by Andrei Neagoie

#### **Skills and Tools**

skills

- Problem solving
- Prototyping
- Design thinking Management
- Working under pressure
  Usability testing
- Information architecture User research

Recruitment

tools

- Adobe XD
- Adobe CC

• Figma

Agile

- Trello
- Git

Javascript

• Html

• CSS

languages

- English (full working proficiency) (native)
- Polish
- Chinese (upper-intermidate)

page 2/2